Guide to the American screen and theater: photographs and lobby cards, 1914-1965 (bulk: 1930-1949)
Department of Special Collections
American screen and theater: photographs and lobby cards,
1914-1965
(bulk: 1930-1949)
Mss Photo 199
4 linear ft. (4 print boxes)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Includes 231 photographs and 231 lobby cards. Some of the photographs are signed by the stars. Many of the productions were performed in San Francisco's Curran and Geary theaters, some in New York and Los Angeles, and only one, "Wedding Bells," in London, 1920. The earliest photographs are from a production in Salt Lake City, "Back to the Country Store," 1914.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Originally part of the Stanford Libraries Theater Collection.
Acquisition Information
Originally part of the Stanford Libraries Theater Collection.
Scope and Content
Includes 231 photographs and 231 lobby cards. Some of the photographs are signed by the stars. Many of the productions were performed in San Francisco's Curran and Geary theaters, some in New York and Los Angeles, and only one, "Wedding Bells," in London, 1920. The earliest photographs are from a production in Salt Lake City, "Back to the Country Store," 1914.
The collection is filed alphabetically by name of production. Playwrights and screenwriters are searchable on the database, as are actors and actresses.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Alda, Robert.; Angelus, Muriel, 1909-; Arden, Eve, 1912-; Ayres, Lew, 1908-; Barrymore, Lionel, 1878-1954.; Belasco, David, 1853-1931.; Bellamy, Ralph, 1904-; Bennett, Richard.; Bergman, Ingrid, 1915-; Blondell, Joan.; Boles, John.; Brazzi, Rossano, 1916-; Brown, Tom, 1913 Jan. 6-; Carlisle, Mary.; Connolly, Walter, 1887-1940.; Cornell, Katharine, 1893-1974.; Crabbe, Buster, 1908-; Crabbe, Larry.; Dell, Gabriel.; Devon, Laura.; Douglas, Melvyn.; Eagels, Jeanne, 1890-1929.; Gargan, William, 1905-; Golbeck, Willis.; Gorcey, Leo B., 1916-1969.; Hall, Huntz, 1920-; Halop, Billy, 1920-1976.; Haugan, Emil.; Hayden, Julie.; Hoctor, Harriet, b. ca. 1939.; Holden, Fay, 1893-1973.; Holliman, Earl, 1928-; Horman, Arthur T., 1904-; Howard, John, 1913-; Hunter, Ian, 1946-; Huntley, George P.; Hussey, Ruth, 1917-; Hutchinson, Josephine, 1904-; Jordan, Bobby.; Jurado, Katy.; Laye, Evelyn.; Lederer, Frances, 1910-1976.; Leslie, Joan, 1925-; Lockhart, Gene, 1891-1957.; Lockhart, Kathleen.; Lorraine, Harriet.; Lubin, Arthur, 1901-; MacDonald, Jeanette, 1903-1965.; MacLane, Barton, 1902-1969.; Maharis, George.; Merivale, Philip, 1886-1946.; Morgan, Frank, 1933-; Nolan, Doris, 1916-; O'Hara, Maureen, 1920-; Parker, Cecilia, 1915-; Price, Vincent.; Punsley, Bernard.; Robinson, Edward G.; Rogers, Will, 1879-1935.; Rooney, Mickey.; Ruskin, Harry, 1894-1969.; Sheridan, Nancy.; Shirley, Anne, 1918-; Stone, Lewis, 1879-1953.; Taylor, Dwight, 1902-1986.; Van Riper, Kay.; Watson, Bobs.; Westley, Helen, 1879-1942.; Young, Annabella.; Young, Robert, 1907-; Curran Theater (San Francisco, Calif.); Geary Theater (San Francisco, Calif.); Motion picture actors and actresses.; Motion pictures--United States--History--20th century.; Theater--United States--History--20th century.; Theater--California--San Francisco.; Theater--London.; Theater Collection.
Collection Contents
- Ah, Wildernessn.d., 4 photographs (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Will Rogers
- Amazing Mr. Wiliams1939, 7 lobby cards (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Dwight Taylor, playwright; Melvyn Douglas, Joan Blondell,
- Andy Hardy Gets Spring Fevern.d., 6 lobby cards (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Kay Van Riper, playwright; Lewis Stone, Mickey Rooney, Cecilia Parker, Fay Holden
- Angels with Dirty Facesn.d., 1 photograph (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Gabriel Dell, Huntz Hall, Billy Halop, Bernard Punsley, Bobby Jordan, Leo B. Gorcey
- Anna Christie1941, 1 photograph (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Ingrid Bergman
- Anne of Green Gables1934, 3 lobby cards (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Anne Shirley, Helen Westley, Tom Brown
- As Good As Married n.d., 1 lobby card (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Doris Nolan, John Boles
- Autumn Crocus1934, 2 photographs (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Frances Lederer, Julie Hayden
- The Bachelor Fathern.d., 2 photographs (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Harriet Lorraine, David Belasco
- Back to the Country Store1914, 2 photographs (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Emil Haugan
- Ballet Revue1934, 3 photographs (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Harriet Hoctor
- The Barretts of Wimpole Streetn.d., 2 photographs (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Katharine Cornell
- Battle of the Villa Fiorita1965, 2 lobby cards (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Maureen O'Hara, Rossano Brazzi
- Belle of the Yukon1944, 1 photograph (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Big Town Czar1939, 5 lobby cards (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Barton MacLane, Tom Brown, Eve Arden, Arthur Lubin
- Bitter Sweetn.d., 9 photographs (Box 1, Folder 16)
  John Howard, Muriel Angelus, Kathleen Lockhart, George P. Huntley, Evelyn Laye
- Blackmailn.d., 6 lobby cards (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Edward G. Robinson, Ruth Hussey, Gene Lockhart, Bobs Watson
- Bridal Suiten.d., 8 lobby cards (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Annabella Young, Robert Young, Gene Lockhart, Walter Connolly
- Broadway Serenaden.d., 3 lobby cards (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Charles Lederer, playwright; Jeanette MacDonald, Lew Ayres, Ian Hunter, Frank Morgan
- Call A Messenger1939, 4 lobby cards (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Arthur T. Horman, playwright; Billy Halop, Huntz Hall, Mary Carlisle, Larry Crabbe
- Calling Dr. Kildaren.d., 6 lobby cards (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Harry Ruskin & Willis Golbeck, screenwriters; Lew Ayres, Lionel Barrymore
- Cardboard Lovern.d., 1 photograph (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Jeanne Eagels
- Cinderella Jonesn.d., 1 lobby cardq (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Joan Leslie, Robert Alda
- Cocktail Partyn.d., 2 photographs (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Vincent Price
- A Covenant With Death1966, 2 lobby cards (Box 1, Folder 25)
  George Maharis; Laura Devon; Katy Jurado; Earl Holliman
- The "Crime" of Dr. Hallet1938, 5 lobby cards (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Josephine Hutchinson; Ralph Bellamy; William Gargan
- Cynaran.d., 1 photograph (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Philip Merivale, Nancy Sheridan
- Cyrano de Bergerac1932, 2 photographs (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Richard Bennett
- Danger on Wheels1939, 5 lobby cards (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Richard Arlen, Andy Devine
- The Dark Angeln.d., 4 photographs (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Dark Passagesn.d., 2 lobby cards (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Delmer Daves, playwright; Humphrey Bogart, Lauren Bacall
- The Darling of the Godsn.d., 2 photographs (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Day-Time Wifen.d., 7 lobby cards (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Art Arthur, playwright; Tyrone Power, Linda Darnell
- Dead Endn.d., 1 photograph (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Desert Songn.d., 2 photographs (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Diamond Liln.d., 2 photographs (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Mae West
- Dishonored Ladyn.d., 1 photograph (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Du Barryn.d., 12 photographs (Box 2, Folder 10)
- The Earl of Chicagon.d., 3 lobby cards (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Robert Montgomery
- Elizabeth the Queenn.d., 5 photographs (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Fast and Furiousn.d., 6 lobby cards (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Harry Kurnitz, playwright; Ruty Husseym, Ann Sothern, Franchot Tone
- The Firebrandn.d., 5 photographs (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Joseph Schild Kraut
- Follow Thru, 2 photographs (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Frolic1934, 1 photograph (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Ruth Mix
- Golden Boy1930, 2 photographs (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Francis Lederer, Betty Furness, Louis Calhern
- Goodnight Ladies1942, 4 photographs (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Buddy Ebsen, Vivian Austin, Skeets Gallagher
- Grand Hotel1932, 2 photographs (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Olga Baclanova, Dorothy Tree, Christian Rub
- The Great Waltzn.d., 1 photograph (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Johann Strauss, Jr.
- Gypsy Baron, 1 photograph (Box 2, Folder 21)
  John Charles Thomas
- Happy-Go-Lucky1936, 5 lobby cards (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Phil Regan, Evelyn Venable
- The Hardys Ride Highn.d., 5 lobby cards (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Agnes Christine Johnson, playwright; Lewis Stone, Mickey Rooney
- Havoc1922 or 1923, 2 photographs (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Hawaiian Nights1939, 6 lobby cards (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Johnny Downs, Mary Carlisle, Constance Moore, Eddie Quillan
- Hearts of the World (film)n.d., 6 photographs (Box 2, Folder 26)
  Bobby Harro, Dorothy Gisa, George Fawcett
- High Stakes1924, 1 photograph (Box 2, Folder 27)
  Lowell Sherman, Robert Vivian
- His Girl Friday1939, 2 lobby cards (Box 2, Folder 28)
  Cary Grant, Rosalind Russell
- Hit the Deckn.d., 5 photographs (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Joan Roberts, June Priesser, Jack Durant, Frankie Albertson, Eddie Foy Jr.
- Hullabaloon.d., 6 lobby cards (Box 2, Folder 30)
  Nat Perrin, playwright; Frank Morgan, Virginia Grey, Dan Dailey Jr.
- Hum Da Di Din.d., 1 photograph (Box 2, Folder 31)
  Maxine Mace, Allen Wood
- I Died A Thousand Timesn.d., 15 lobby cards (Box 2, Folder 32)
  Jack Palance, Shelley Winters
- I Take This Womann.d., 4 lobby cards (Box 2, Folder 33)
  James Kevin McGuinness, playwright; Spencer Tracy, Hedy Lamarr
- It's a Daten.d., 7 lobby cards (Box 2, Folder 34)
  Deanna Durbin, Walter Pidgeon, Kay Francis
- It's a Wise Child1929 or 1930, 1 photograph (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Journey's Endn.d., 2 photographs (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Hugh Williams, Forrester Harvey, Walter Hudd
- Jubal1956, 2 lobby cards (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Glenn Ford, Ernest Borgnine, Rod Steiger
- The Keeper of the Bees1935, 5 lobby cards (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Neil Hamilton, Betty Furness, Emma Dunn
- Kiss Me, Katen.d., 1 photograph (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Bob Wright, Jean Fenn
- Lady by Choice1934, 3 lobby cards (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Walter Connolly, May Robson, Roger Pryor,
- Little Nellie Kellyn.d., 12 photographs (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Alice Cavanaugh, Lester Cole
- Little Orchid Annien.d., 1 photograph (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Lucky Nightn.d., 1 lobby card (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Myrna Loy, Robert Taylor
- Lulu Bellen.d., 4 photographs (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Maisien.d., 5 lobby cards (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Robert Young, Ann Sothern
- The Man Who Came to Dinnern.d., 2 photographs (Box 3, Folder 11)
- March of Time1939, 2 lobby cards, 1 informational flyer (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Marie Galante1934, 1 lobby card (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Ketti Gallian, Spencer Tracy
- Men in White1934, 1 photograph (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Betty Lawford, Roger Pryor
- The Merchant of Venicen.d., 8 photographs (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Maude Adams, Charles Laughton
- The Merry Widow1940, 2 photographs (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Jarmila Novotna, John Ehrle, Helen Gahagan
- The Mighty Barnum1934, 1 lobby card (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Ten Miles of Heavenn.d., 1 photograph (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Miracles for Sale, 5 lobby cards (Box 3, Folder 19)
  Robert young, Florence Rice
- Mountain Justice1937, 5 lobby cards (Box 3, Folder 20)
  Josephine Hutchinson, George Brent
- Mrs. Moonlight1932, 1 photograph (Box 3, Folder 21)
  Clara Verder
- Mulatton.d., 1 photograph (Box 3, Folder 22)
  James Kirkwood, Evelyn Streich
- Music is in My Heart1939, 7 lobby cards (Box 3, Folder 23)
  Tony Martin, Rita Hayworth
- Music is in the Airn.d., John Charles Thoms, Irra Petina (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Music is Magic1935, 2 lobby cards (Box 3, Folder 25)
  Alice Faye, Ray Walker, Bebe Daniels
- New Moonn.d., 1 photograph (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Oh, Susannan.d., 4 photographs (Box 3, Folder 27)
- On Moonlight Bay1951, 1 lobby card (Box 3, Folder 28)
  Doris Day, Gordon MacRae
- On the Spotn.d., 1 photograph (Box 3, Folder 29)
  Anna May Wong
- Once in a Lifetimen.d., 2 photographs (Box 3, Folder 30)
- One Hour to Live1939, 3 lobby cards (Box 3, Folder 31)
- The Outlawn.d., Jean Harlow (Box 3, Folder 32)
- The Painted Veiln.d., 3 photographs (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Pardon Our Nerven.d., 5 lobby cards (Box 3, Folder 34)
  Robert Ellis, playwright; Lynn Bari
- Parrish1961, 2 lobby cards (Box 3, Folder 35)
  Troy Donahue, Claudette Colbert
- Peter Ibbetsonn.d., 1 photograph (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Peter Pann.d., 6 photograghs (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Porgy and Bessn.d., 2 photographs (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Prison Without Bars1939, 4 lobby cards (Box 3, Folder 39)
  Edna Best, Barry Barnes, Corinne Luchaire
- Professor Beware1938, 1 lobby card (Box 3, Folder 40)
  Delmer Daves and Jack Cunningham, playwrights; Lionel Stander, Phyllis Welch, Raymond Walburn
- The Queen's Husbandn.d., 5 photographs (Box 3, Folder 41)
- The Rains Came1939, 5 lobby cards (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Myrna Loy, Tyrone Power, George Brent
- Reaching for the Moon1931, 3 photographs (Box 4, Folder 2)
- The Red Mill1940, 1 photograph (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Dorothy Stone, Charles Collins
- Rose Marien.d., 1 photograph (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Saint Joann.d., 1 photograph (Box 4, Folder 5)
- School for Scandaln.d., 3 photographs (Box 4, Folder 6)
- The Shanghai Gesturen.d., 1 photograph (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Mrs. Leslie Carter
- She Loves Me Notn.d., 2 photographs (Box 4, Folder 8)
- 6000 Enemiesn.d., 6 lobby cards (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Walter Pidgeon, Rita Johnson
- Small Town Girl1953, Dorothy Cooper, Dorothy Kinsley, screewriters (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Jane Powell, Farley Granger
- Song of Norwayn.d., 4 photographs (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Muriel O'Malley, Jean Fenn, John Tyers,
- Spencer's Mountain1963, 2 lobby cards (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Henry Fonda, Maureen O'Hara, James MacArthur
- Springtime for Henry1932, 1 photograph (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Laura La Plante, Edward Everett Horton
- Story to be Whispered 1937, 1 photograph (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Stronger Than Desiren.d., 5 lobby cards (Box 4, Folder 15)
  David Hertz, William Ludwig, screenwriters; Virginia Bruce, Walter Pidgeon
- A Summer Place1963, 2 lobby cards (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Richard Egan, Dorothy McGuire, Sandra Dee, Arthur Kennedy, Troy Donahue
- Susan and Godn.d., 5 photographs (Box 4, Folder 17)
  Joan Crawford, Fredric March
- Susan Slade1961, 2 lobby cards (Box 4, Folder 18)
  Troy Donahue, Connie Stevens, Dorothy McGuire, Lloyd Nolan
- Tattle Tales, 1 photograph (Box 4, Folder 19)
  Felix Young, Barbara Syanwyck
- Tea for Two1950, 2 lobby cards (Box 4, Folder 20)
- These Glamour Girlsn.d., 3 lobby cards (Box 4, Folder 21)
  Jane Hall, Marion Parsonnet, screenwriters; Lew Ayres, Lana Turner, Tom Brown, Jane Bryan, RIchard Carlson, Anita Louise
- Three Fates1957, 9 photographs, informational sheet (Box 4, Folder 22)
  M. Sidorkin, producer
- Three Live Ghosts1929, 5 photographs (Box 4, Folder 23)
  Charles MacNaughton, Robert Montgomery, Claude Allister
- The Time of Your Lifen.d., 1 photograph (Box 4, Folder 24)
  William Saroyan, author; Eddie Dowling, Julie Haydon
- Too Busy to Work1938, 6 lobby cards (Box 4, Folder 25)
  Robert Ellis, Helen Logan, Stanley Rauh, screenwriters; Jed Prouty, Spring Byington, Ken Howell, George ERnest, June Carlson
- Top of the Hilln.d., 3 photographs (Box 4, Folder 26)
  Helda Vaughn, Anderson Lawler, Helen Menkey
- Tovarich1937, 2 photographs, 2 sheets (6 photos on each) (Box 4, Folder 27)
  Eugenie Leontovich, Osgood Perkins, Melville Cooper
- Tropic Fury1939, 2 photographs (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Up In Armsn.d., 2 photographs (Box 4, Folder 29)
  Samuel Goldwyn, playwright; Danny Kaye, Dinah Shore
- The Vagabond King1942, 9 photographs (Box 4, Folder 30)
  Kathreen Van Brunt, Bob Lawrence, John Carradinse Melville Cooper, Vera Marshe, Marthe Errolle
- The Vinegar Tree1931, 1 photograph (Box 4, Folder 31)
  Warren William
- The Waltz King1943, 1944, 2 photographs (Box 4, Folder 32)
  Richard Bonelli, Marjorie Cooke, Virginia Card
- Wedding Bells1920, 3 photographs (Box 4, Folder 33)
  Edith Evans, Gladys Cooper, John Deverill
- White Cargo1925, 2 photographs (Box 4, Folder 34)
- For Whom the Bell Tolls1957, 1 lobby card (Box 4, Folder 35)
  Ernest Hemingway, author; Gary Cooper, Ingrid Bergman
- Winner Take All1939, 7 lobby cards (Box 4, Folder 36)
  Tony Martin, Gloria Stuart, Henry Armetta, Slim Summerville, Kane Richmond
- The Wiser Sex1932, 1 lobby card (Box 4, Folder 37)
  Claudette Colbert, Melvyn Douglas, Lilyan Tashman, William Boyd
- The Witness Vanishes1939, 5 lobby cards (Box 4, Folder 38)
  Robertson White, screenwriter; Edmund Lowe, Wendy Barrie, Bruce Lester
- The Wonder Bar, 3 photographs, 2 sketches (Box 4, Folder 39)
  Claire Windsor, Al Jolson, Rita Montaner, Luana Alconiz
- Young Blood Hawke1964, 2 lobby cards (Box 4, Folder 40)
  Herman Wouk, novelist; Suzanne Pleshett, Genevieve Page, James Franciscus